9 Years Earlier
Sinack Village, Festival of Thanksgiving
It's not fair. They only treat me
like a kid at times like these.
Ow...
I'm here on a nighty call, Ikta!
You, huh?
You scared me, Nana.
So?
What's a nighty call?
You don't know about it?
On the night of a festival,
a woman goes and visits
a man she likes in bed.
And?
What happens next?
Well...
I think you go to sleep together?
You can't do anything if you fall asleep.
That's true...
Wanna chat, then?
Grandma, grandpa...
You goddamn barbarian!
Hey, wait.
She's a woman.
Our army...
It's out of control.
Captain, send Yatori's platoon and mine in!
Not yet!
There are too many of them rampaging—
If we don't go now, it'll be too late!
Get off, damn it!
I'm the superior officer, so I go first!
Shut up.
Who gives a shit about your rank?
Hey, you guys need to cut that crap out.
That's an awfully condescending tone.
Why the hell should I listen
to a mere warrant officer?
Don't think I'm always
going to have an answer
that you people are going to accept.
Yatori, secure Nana.
It's better if a girl does it.
She's fine.
We made it in time.
I see.
This time, we made it.
I don't care if you're a hero or a warrior.
But I've got no patience for beasts.
La Saia Alderamin
This is about the worst ending possible,
but it shouldn't be possible for the Sinack
to put up an organized fight anymore.
This war is at an end.
An end...
It's over...
Looks like we'll make it home in one piece.
Yeah.
Didn't expect this battle
to be so rough, though.
There were too many problems
with our higher-ups.
And we weren't just facing the Sinack.
What do you mean?
Those guys who showed up at
the end of the last battle
were probably Kala Karm.
Kala Karm?
Yeah.
The Ghost Squad.
A special forces unit of the Kioka army.
Wait.
Are you telling me Kioka was
involved in the Sinack rebellion?
Their tactics were far too efficient.
The assassination of Major Toakk,
those mountain guerrilla warfare tactics...
And...
Ikkun, they've got them, too?
That's right. They're using air rifles.
Oh, right...
If anyone else had an air rifle,
it would have to be the Kioka Republic,
where Dr. Anarai fled.
That's right.
Hello, men!
Looks like you taught those Sinack
barbarians quite the lesson, huh?
This is—
We are an Aldera inspection team.
Is the man in charge here available?
I am Lieutenant General Tamtooktsk Safida,
commander of the Northern Garrison!
What do you want?
We received a message that
the commandments of the Aldera religion
were being violated in the Northern Region.
The suspected location is
the Northern Garrison,
and the violation is abuse
of the Four Great Spirits.
We were sent to investigate the truth.
But...
It seems there's no need to even bother.
Wait! We have our reasons!
If you want to make excuses,
you can do it after official censure
arrives from headquarters.
Chase him!
Huh?
Go after them and stop them!
Pick a company that's still
got spirit and send them!
A company that's got spirit?
La Saia Alderamin?
The army of the nation of Aldera?
They hold those flag upright
and bring out their army
only when executing holy duties...
Wh-What do you mean?
Military invasion of another country,
performed in the name of God.
Oh, no...
They've been ready for this for a long time,
and this was just their last warning
before beginning the war.
This is bad.
That's right.
The Northern Garrison is exhausted.
This is the worst possible time.
It's like someone set us up...
Ah... so that's it!
There were Aldera pilgrimage clothes
left where Major Toakk was killed.
We know the Sinack used them
to conceal their identity,
but why pilgrimage clothes?
However, if you put Kioka in the mix,
it all makes sense...
Kioka was manipulating the Sinack,
and they spurred the priests of
Aldera into invading the Empire.
They've got quite the strategist
on their side.
The Holy Army of Aldera
is right in front of us!
We must either retreat
with all forces, or fight!
You can at least make that decision, right?
I have a suggestion.
We should put a retreat
support unit to our rear
and attempt to delay the enemy.
Yeah, that's the only way!
That's right!
We have less than 8,000 soldiers,
and if we wish to continue
a defensive battle,
we'll need at least 6,000
to make it back to base.
Which means we have at most 2,000
to use for retreat support.
The question is how we use these forces...
My aides will explain the rest.
Before we can begin a defensive battle
to buy time for a retreat,
we'll need to draw out a first battle
to make time to prepare.
We can use a single battalion
of around 600 for this.
Wait!
Can 600 delay a force of 12,000?
We'll explain the exact plan later,
but since I was the one who
came up with this plan,
I, Senpa Sazaluf, would like to be in charge.
Oh, I have a suggestion
on the manpower issue.
We'll have the Sinack help
make up the missing numbers.
What? You're going to make the Sinack help?
Why did you undo the ropes?
Apologizing to someone when
you've tied them up in ropes
is just another way of threatening them.
Apologize?
You won the war! Why would
you apologize to the losers?!
For the inhumane acts we committed.
Shut the hell up!
Having the winners look
down on you and apologize
is an insult to a warrior!
You're correct.
I have no intention of apologizing
for the inhumanity of war itself.
But we do have to apologize for
the senseless violence and slaughter
of the non-combatants under our jurisdiction.
A hackneyed apology certainly
isn't enough to erase our crimes.
And it won't bring back the dead.
I heard a story once.
A hunter who lived in Alafatra
once mistakenly shot a girl with his bow.
He used all his wealth buying gifts to atone,
and uttered every word of
apology he could think of.
But the girl's father
silently handed him a small dagger.
The hunter realized what was asked of him.
If he used the dagger,
he could avoid ever making the same mistake,
ever again.
Ever since then,
the Sinack have cut off their fingers
as a traditional way of showing apology.
That's the old story you
told me, wasn't it, Nana?
W-Wait...
You're...
Ikta Solork, Warrant Officer
in the Imperial Military.
A lot's happened, and now
my last name's different.
Is that really you, Ikta?
It's been a long time, Nana.
This really isn't the time,
but you've grown up to be very pretty.
Nana...
I know I don't have the right to ask,
but I want three favors.
The first is
that you accept my apology for our misdeeds.
The second is
that the Sinack help us repel
the Holy Army of Aldera.
I don't know if this will make it worth it,
but I'll cut twice more...
as my way of apologizing!
They're trying to strike the Sinack and the
Northern Garrison while we're exhausted
in order to wipe us both out.
So the Aldera nation has
crossed the stairs of God
to invade the Empire?
They intend to crush both
the Sinack and the Northern Garrison
in the name of saving the spirits.
More precisely, the Aldera army
itself is just a pawn.
The ones who set this up were the ones
who taught you guerrilla tactics,
as well as the term "holy war."
You can't mean...
That's right.
The Kioka Republic.
If the nation of Aldera takes control here,
they'll show no mercy to
the Sinack's heretical beliefs.
All I can say is that if you help me here,
I can guarantee a place for the Sinack
in the Empire when this is all done.
Is that a personal proposal?
It's the proposal of the
entire Northern Garrison.
I won't let them break their promise.
I know it's selfish, but there's no time.
I want you to make your decision here,
Chieftain of the Sinack.
What's the last one?
You've only made two unreasonable requests.
Oh, that might be the most important.
I'd like you to let me keep calling you Nana.
No way...
Just for that you...
The first and second were my way
of apologizing as a soldier.
The third was my apology as your friend.
If you'd grown up to be a worse person,
I wouldn't have had to worry about anything.
Yeah?
I cut off my pinky without hesitation
because you grew up into
such a splendid woman.
All right.
You may not have the right to ask,
but as Chieftain of the Sinack,
I, Nanaku Daru, accept!
Hey, did you know that fingers don't
grow back after you cut them off?
Why didn't you say something?
No, I'm sorry.
I didn't have a choice.
There wasn't time to convince her with words.
It wasn't your unit that went out of control.
Negotiations with Nana were
only possible through me,
so that was just how it ended up.
Ikkun, did it work?
She said she'll send 800 men in two days.
We have to be grateful
to Captain Sazaluf, too.
He put everyone from the
burned villages in one place,
so it won't take long to gather people.
Thank you.
I apologize for the trouble, Captain.
Hey, that's not like you.
I was the one who decided to
play along with your proposal.
Anyway, time to give you
Lieutenant General Safida's rewards.
First, Warrant Officer Ikta,
Warrant Officer Yatorishino.
Congratulations on field promotions!
From now on, you're first lieutenants!
Warrant Officers Matthew, Torway, and Haroma.
From now on, your official rank
is second lieutenant.
What?
What's with that? You should be happier!
Once we're back, you can show off!
If we make it back, sure...
Second Lieutenant Matthew.
Second Lieutenant Haroma.
If you want,
I can send you and your units
to the rear right now.
But, wait, didn't they already decide who
would be in the retreat support unit?
It's not officially completed, no.
Matthew, my opinion of you's changed a lot.
You were clearly a splendid
commanding officer.
I think you can be proud.
You too, Haro.
Without your unit,
there would've been far more casualties.
I'm honored.
You'll both make excellent officers.
So take this opportunity
to learn when to pull out.
Yatori said everything I wanted to say.
But, Torway,
I'm going to apologize to you while I can.
I don't have a replacement for
your unit and their air rifles.
This is goodbye for a while, you two,
but next time we meet—
Who the hell do you people think you are?!
Let me ask one thing.
Have I ever hindered you
in any battles so far?
No,
you were a reliable comrade.
If you really mean that,
why the hell are you telling
your "comrade" to run away first?!
Ma-kun...
This battle is going to be
a tightrope walk, Matthew!
Yeah!
Many of your men might die.
One wrong move and you'll die, too.
Even a little bad luck means—
Yeah!
That's true for you, too,
and you're going anyway, right?
If I'm there, will I slow you down?
I take it all back.
I'm sorry, Matthew, my friend.
I apologize as well.
Please lend us your help
in the battle to come.
Y-You should've just said that
from the start.
I'll stay, too!
The Knights are where I belong!
Let me help protect you,
even a little, please!
I'm sorry, Haro,
for underestimating your resolve.
Right!
Ah, to be young again.
I could use your help with
something right now, Haro...
Huh? What happened?
Huh? Huh?!
Ikta-san! Your finger!
Your finger!
Great Forest of Gagal Kasakan
2 Days Later
As usual, Ikta's plan is bold,
but we've got three and a half days.
Manpower and time are limited.
If a 12,000 strong Alderan force
wants to invade Katjvarna,
they'll have to come through the
Great Forest of Gagal Kasakan.
So they're going to burn
the whole forest down?
Madness!
That's exactly what you see when
you've driven someone to the brink.
However, if we waste too much time here,
it will hinder our pursuit.
I know that!
Maybe we could put the fire out
if we all pissed on it?
General Akugalpa,
that's a very creative idea,
but no.
What a pain.
Hey, Mishuri, is that kid here yet?
I've sent someone for him, but...
I don't know if it's wise
to rely on him so much.
Even if he's a guest officer,
if he's part of our chain of command,
he's just another one of my men!
What's wrong with running him hard?
Looks like we made it in time.
It's burning nicely.
Right, Kus?
Ikta, the wound on your
left hand opened again.
If you don't get it treated,
it will get infected.
When it really hurts,
you should talk to someone.
I'm not just talking about your injury.
Haro, do I look like the type to
keep my problems to myself?
I heard from Yatori
that you were once close
to the Sinack Chieftain.
I don't think there's been a single
moment since this war started
when you haven't been enduring
some kind of pain, has there?
That's an exaggeration.
You seem to carry a lot more burdens
than other people do.
The enemy's taken action.
They set a fire to burn ours out?
That's a bold move.
And they made the decision unusually fast.
They were a neutral country with
no big wars for over a century.
Could they really do something
so effective so fast?
La Saia Alderamin is provided
advisers by the Empire
and the Republic to maintain
its military strength.
A guest officer?
There's something I heard
when I was at a Central base.
The Kioka officer who was
sent to La Saia Alderamin
was still young, but his hair
was white like an old man's.
He worked harder than anyone, day and night.
No one had ever seen him lying down.
It's like God made him to
keep the balance with me.
Yes, I thought the same thing
when I heard the rumors.
I believe the moniker they gave him was
"The Unsleeping, Shining Officer."
I'm coming in, Jean.
I've brought tea.
Kioka Army First Lieutenant Miara Gin
You're burning through quite
a bit of our paper resources...
Is something bothering you?
The Unsleeping, Shining Officer
Kioka Army Major Jean Alkiniks
I was drawing up the tactical
deployments from here out.
This seems like it will be tough.
Tough?
We haven't had a single
battle yet, though.
The enemy quickly gave up
on a real counterattack,
and put all their energy into
buying time for the retreat.
Who was it
that was capable of making a
desperate plan like that succeed
for the Empire at the 11th hour?
August, Imperial Year 906.
The greatest prodigy of his time had
been sent to the Holy Army of Aldera.
People called him
the Unsleeping, Shining Officer.
Kioka Army Major Jean Alkiniks.
Next Time: Lazy vs. Unsleeping.
Lazy vs. Unsleeping